Relevant experience

Web Developer

July 2023 — current | DialAFlight

- I develop and maintain the main business site, using TypeScript and SCSS.
- I work closely with the design team, ensuring the timely completion of UI updates.
- Using the Google Maps api, I added hotel location and search functionality.

Web Developer

May 2022 — June 2023 | 5874 Commerce

- Working with the BigCommerce platform, I built and maintained ecommerce sites for a variety of clients.
- I also used React.js and TypeScript to build headless projects with robust, strongly-typed UI components.
- With the Redux library or the useContext hook, I maintained app state across a variety of projects.
- I mentored junior members of the team, suggesting code improvements and opportunities for further learning.

Frontend Developer

January 2022 - April 2022 | Distinction

- Collaborating with the design team, I built modern, responsive UIs from Figma design boards.
- I created reusable, responsive site components with the Vue.js framework.
- I fixed frontend bugs quickly and effectively.

Junior Software Developer

March 2021 - January 2022 | MyBalance

- I built and maintained a blog site with Next.js.
- Using React Native, I designed and updated mobile app components, ensuring cross-device functionality.
- With Figma, I designed user journeys and mobile views.

Rhys Jenkins

Mobile: 07577 627643

Email: 89rhysjenkins@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/RhysJenkins89

Summary

I am a diligent, creative web developer with three years of experience working with some of the most popular frontend frameworks and platforms.

I'm most comfortable with React.js, but my fundamental HTML, CSS, and JavaScript/ TypeScript skills are strong.

What's more, I have a practical, can-do attitude to software development, and I'm keen to move into a role in which I can continue to learn new skills.

I'm currently building

For my current personal project, I'm building a geography learning app with React Native and TypeScript. At the moment, I'm working on functionality for users to learn the world's capital cities. Find the project on my GitHub.

Technologies

• React.js

Next.js

JavaScript

TypeScript

• HTML

CSS/SCSS

• Tailwind CSS

• BigCommerce

• WordPress

• Firebase

Webpack

• Git

Education

University of Salford, 2010 – 2013 English Literature, 2:1